<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Admin | Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/peppermint21/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Placement Services</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 02:30:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Two Tips for Moving Elderly Parents</title>
		<link>/two-tips-for-moving-elderly-parents/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 02:30:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Two Tips for Moving Elderly Parents While it may look simple, moving elderly parents from their current home or apartment to a new home can be very difficult without the... <a href="/two-tips-for-moving-elderly-parents/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/two-tips-for-moving-elderly-parents/">Two Tips for Moving Elderly Parents</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">Two Tips for Moving Elderly Parents</p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">While it may look simple, moving elderly parents from their current home or apartment to a new home can be very difficult without the proper knowledge or assistance. You may wonder as to what is the best way to help in moving your elderly parent when they are agitated, unsure, or depressed. </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Whether their new home is close by or far away, here are two ways that you can make the transition smoother for everyone.</span></p>
<ol>
<li class="p1"><span class="s1">Bring what is important to them</span></li>
</ol>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Moving to a new home can be a very emotionally charged process for both you and your loved one. It can be a comfort to your elderly parents if they keep items that are important to them, and bring them to their new home. Make sure to ask their new home if there are any restrictions on what they can bring. Having items they care about and that remind them of who they are, and what they care about, will help your loved one maintain who they are and their unique sense of identity wherever they go.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">      2. Help them pack</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Help your loved one pack, but let them tell you what items they want to include in their new home/room. Also, plan to talk it out with them well before beginning to pack if there is anything you have an issue with them bringing, or that you think would not be safe (a commemorative knife, for example).</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">As always, if you need assistance locating a new home for your loved one, Peppermint Palm Placement Services is here to help you find senior placement in California, senior placement in Sacramento, or senior placement in the Bay Area. We can help in multiple states and throughout California.</span></p>The post <a href="/two-tips-for-moving-elderly-parents/">Two Tips for Moving Elderly Parents</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beat the Heat! Tips for Seniors to Stay Healthy in the Heat</title>
		<link>/beat-the-heat-tips-for-seniors-to-stay-healthy-in-the-heat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 20:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; Tips for Seniors to Stay Healthy in the Heat! Take measures to stay cool, remain hydrated, and keep informed. Getting too hot can make you sick. You can become... <a href="/beat-the-heat-tips-for-seniors-to-stay-healthy-in-the-heat/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/beat-the-heat-tips-for-seniors-to-stay-healthy-in-the-heat/">Beat the Heat! Tips for Seniors to Stay Healthy in the Heat</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Tips for Seniors to Stay Healthy in the Heat!</p>
<p>Take measures to stay cool, remain hydrated, and keep informed. Getting too hot can make you sick. You can become ill from the heat if your body can’t compensate for it and properly cool you off. The main things affecting your body’s ability to cool itself during extremely hot weather are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>High humidity.</strong> When the humidity is high, sweat won’t evaporate as quickly, which keeps your body from releasing heat as fast as it may need to.</li>
<li><strong>Personal factors.</strong> Age, obesity, fever, dehydration, heart disease, mental illness, poor circulation, sunburn, and prescription drug and alcohol use can play a role in whether a person can cool off enough in very hot weather.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><img decoding="async" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1216" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/extremeheat_a250px-1.jpg" alt="extremeheat_a250px" width="250" height="167" /></strong><strong>Those who are at highest risk include people 65 and older, children younger than two, and people with chronic diseases or mental illness.</strong>  Closely monitor people who depend on you for their care and ask these questions<strong>:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Are they drinking enough water?</li>
<li>Do they have access to air conditioning?</li>
<li>Do they need help keeping cool?</li>
</ul>
<p>People at greatest risk for heat-related illness can take the following protective actions to prevent illness or death:</p>
<ul>
<li>Stay in air-conditioned buildings as much as possible. Contact your local health department or locate an air-conditioned shelter in your area. Air-conditioning is the number one protective factor against heat-related illness and death. If a home is not air-conditioned, people can reduce their risk for heat-related illness by spending time in public facilities that are air-conditioned, and using air conditioning in vehicles.</li>
<li>Do not rely on a fan as your primary cooling device during an extreme heat event.</li>
<li>Drink more water than usual and <strong>don’t wait</strong> until you’re thirsty to drink.</li>
<li>Check on a friend or neighbor and have someone do the same for you.</li>
<li>Don’t use the stove or oven to cook—it will make you and your house hotter.</li>
</ul>
<p>VIA: <span style="text-decoration: underline;">https://www.cdc.gov/features/extremeheat/index.html</span></p>The post <a href="/beat-the-heat-tips-for-seniors-to-stay-healthy-in-the-heat/">Beat the Heat! Tips for Seniors to Stay Healthy in the Heat</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding Friends Over 60</title>
		<link>/finding-new-friends-over-60/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 20:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As we age, it can get harder and harder to maintain old friendships and find new ones. Yet, friendships improve our happiness and wellbeing. Read below for our tips on... <a href="/finding-new-friends-over-60/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/finding-new-friends-over-60/">Finding Friends Over 60</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we age, it can get harder and harder to maintain old friendships and find new ones. Yet, friendships improve our happiness and wellbeing. Read below for our tips on how to find new friends over 60<img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-1186 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/friendship-elderly-lifespan-300x200.jpg" alt="friendship-elderly-lifespan" width="300" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/friendship-elderly-lifespan-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/friendship-elderly-lifespan.jpg 610w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />.</p>
<p><strong>#1 Say YES!</strong></p>
<p>Adopt a positive attitude, even when joining a new group or activity may seem nerve-wracking. Pick an activity that you are interested in, research local opportunities, then drop in and see if you can meet some kindred spirits.</p>
<p><strong>#2 Initiate and Invite</strong></p>
<p>When you feel ready to have new people in your home, consider inviting people to a casual dinner or pot luck. This is a great way to get to know people in a comfortable setting.</p>
<p><strong>#3 Make Friendship a Priority</strong></p>
<p>Once you have a few people that you like to spend time with, remember that to maintain the bond, you have to set aside time for them. It&#8217;s easier than ever to chat or text by phone, but remember to put in the work of getting together once a week in person.</p>The post <a href="/finding-new-friends-over-60/">Finding Friends Over 60</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get More Done in Less Time!</title>
		<link>/get-more-done-in-less-time/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 01:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As a caregiver, you can be busy&#8211;to say the least! Peppermint Palm Senior Care provides senior placement services in Assisted Living/RCFEs, but we also like to give you tips to... <a href="/get-more-done-in-less-time/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/get-more-done-in-less-time/">Get More Done in Less Time!</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a caregiver, you can be busy&#8211;to say the least! Peppermint Palm Senior Care provides senior placement services in Assisted Living/RCFEs, but we also like to give you tips to manage your life, no matter what level of care you need. These tips will help you <strong>get more done</strong>, have a <strong>clearer mind</strong>, and <strong>feel energetic</strong> and productive!</p>
<div id="attachment_1182" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1182" class="size-medium wp-image-1182" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/dd46bf8c-f896-405c-9c8a-c526b98572a6-300x187.jpg" alt="Placement Services in Sacramento and the Bay Area." width="300" height="187" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/dd46bf8c-f896-405c-9c8a-c526b98572a6-300x187.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/02/dd46bf8c-f896-405c-9c8a-c526b98572a6.jpg 700w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /><p id="caption-attachment-1182" class="wp-caption-text">Placement Services in Sacramento and the Bay Area.</p></div>
<p><span style="color: #4b0082;"><strong>?</strong></span><strong> Work Better and Feel Healthier&#8211;Now! </strong><span style="color: #4b0082;"><strong>?</strong></span></p>
<div>
<p><strong>#1: Use A 1-3-5 List</strong><br />
Don&#8217;t overestimate the number of things you can get done in a day. Plan to get <strong>one large task, three medium-sized tasks, and five small tasks</strong> done every day.</p>
<p><strong>#2: Write down what’s bugging you.</strong><br />
Put those nagging thoughts on paper. <strong>Clearing your mind</strong> of mental clutter will help you to <strong>accomplish more</strong> and<strong> be calm.</strong></p>
</div>
<p>We find placement for adults throughout the Bay Area and in Northern California, as well as Sacramento. Locating Assisted Living in Sacramento or Assisted Living in the Bay Area can be difficult, but with our resources we have helped many&#8211;and can help you too!</p>The post <a href="/get-more-done-in-less-time/">Get More Done in Less Time!</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Advice for Caregivers</title>
		<link>/advice-for-caregivers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 06:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Tips for Managing Caregiver Stress Is it hard being a caregiver? Absolutely it is hard being a caregiver! Caregiver stress and burnout is a real phenomenon. That&#8217;s why when the... <a href="/advice-for-caregivers/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/advice-for-caregivers/">Advice for Caregivers</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Tips for Managing Caregiver Stress</h1>
<div>
<p>Is it hard being a caregiver? Absolutely it is hard being a caregiver! Caregiver stress and burnout is a real phenomenon. That&#8217;s why when the time comes, Peppermint Palm Senior Care&#8217;s senior placement services in Assisted Living/RCFE make your life easier! We handle placement throughout the Bay Area and in Sacramento. Finding Assisted Living in Sacramento or Assisted Living in the Bay Area can be difficult, but with our resources we can help.</p>
<p>However, if you are feeling stressed as a caregiver, here are tips for managing your caregiver stress, and caregiver stress symptoms.<br />
<img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" wp-image-1176 alignright" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/emotions-2713109_960_720-300x200.jpg" alt="emotions-2713109_960_720" width="438" height="292" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/emotions-2713109_960_720-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/emotions-2713109_960_720-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/emotions-2713109_960_720.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 438px) 100vw, 438px" /></p>
</div>
<p align="left">
<strong>#1: Stop Multitasking</strong><br />
Experts have connected multitasking to increased stress and poor memory. Do one thing at a time, and limit your cell phone and e-mail use to working hours only. If you are using senior placement services, we can call at a time that&#8217;s best for you!</p>
<p><strong>#2: Recall a Past Success</strong></p>
<p>Taking five minutes to reflect on how you succeeded in other stressful situations can help you be more calm.</p>
<p align="left"><strong>#3: Focus on Your Senses for a Few Minutes</strong></p>
<p>For just a few minutes a day, practice mindfulness—focus only on what&#8217;s going on in the present. Focus on what you see, feel, hear, smell.</p>The post <a href="/advice-for-caregivers/">Advice for Caregivers</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2 Healthy New Years Resolutions</title>
		<link>/2-healthy-new-years-resolutions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>     1. Stop Drinking. Studies show that the rate of hip fractures in older adults increases with alcohol use. Drinking too much alcohol over a long time can have the... <a href="/2-healthy-new-years-resolutions/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/2-healthy-new-years-resolutions/">2 Healthy New Years Resolutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>     1. <img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class="size-medium wp-image-1171 alignleft" src="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/new-years-eve-114011_960_720-300x200.jpg" alt="healthy new years resolutions for seniors" width="300" height="200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/new-years-eve-114011_960_720-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/new-years-eve-114011_960_720-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2018/01/new-years-eve-114011_960_720.jpg 960w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" />Stop Drinking.</strong> Studies show that the rate of hip fractures in older adults increases with alcohol use.</p>
<p>Drinking too much alcohol over a long time can have the following effects upon Adults:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lead to some kinds of cancer, liver damage, immune system disorders, and brain damage</li>
<li>Worsen some health conditions like memory loss and diabetes, as well as mood disorders</li>
<li>Make some medical problems hard for doctors to find and treat—for example, alcohol causes changes in the heart and blood vessels.</li>
<li>Cause some older people to be forgetful and confused—these symptoms could be mistaken for signs of Alzheimers Disease.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2. Talk to your loved one about their anxiety or depression. </strong></p>
<ul style="list-style-type: disc;">
<li>If you’re concerned about an older person experiencing anxiety, depression, suicidal thoughts, or just not coping, then it is important to take the first step. Begin a conversation; your support and concern may make all the difference.</li>
</ul>The post <a href="/2-healthy-new-years-resolutions/">2 Healthy New Years Resolutions</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Understanding Your Parent’s Grief</title>
		<link>/understanding-your-parents-grief/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 20:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Understanding Your Parent’s Grief A grieving person can’t function at 100 percent, so the initial months after your parent’s death aren’t a time for your parent to start new projects... <a href="/understanding-your-parents-grief/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/understanding-your-parents-grief/">Understanding Your Parent’s Grief</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Understanding Your Parent’s Grief</strong></p>
<p>A grieving person can’t function at 100 percent, so the initial months after your parent’s death aren’t a time for your parent to start new projects or make major decisions. Their normal functions will return, even though you may find them doing abnormal things. Such behavior isn’t surprising; they are grieving. Signs of grief include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Forgetfulness. Your usually organized parent may miss appointments, lock their keys in the car or mail unsigned checks with his bills. You can help them by being patient, reminding them that these are symptoms of grief and suggesting that he write down reminders to themselves.</li>
<li>Disorganization. Your parent may find that it takes a lot longer to finish everyday tasks. He may not manage their time well — leaving one project unfinished and going on to something else. You might help them plan a schedule, or offer to work with them. Spending time together and focusing on something other than the grief can bring you closer together, as well as ease their sense of isolation and loneliness.</li>
<li>Inability to concentrate. During the early stages of bereavement, the mind wanders. Your newly widowed parent may find it impossible to stay focused. It may be difficult for them to read a book or even to stick with a TV show. Reading a newspaper may take longer than before, and retaining information may be difficult. You can help by highlighting important points, or even reading aloud with them. Bereaved people can be dangerous on the highways due to their inability to concentrate. They’re also susceptible to unexpected crying spells. Warn your parent to be extra careful when driving or handling potentially dangerous equipment, such as a lawn mower or even a garbage disposal in a sink.</li>
<li>Lack of interest or motivation. Your parent might say: “Why work so hard? We just die anyway” or “I was doing all this for your mother/father, and now they&#8217;re dead. Why bother?” Let them express their feelings, and offer them love and support. But if you worry that he might actually hurt themselves, or if you notice them dealing with their sadness by using alcohol or drugs, talk to their physician immediately.</li>
</ul>
<p>from: https://americanhospice.org/working-through-grief/helping-a-grieving-parent/</p>The post <a href="/understanding-your-parents-grief/">Understanding Your Parent’s Grief</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</title>
		<link>/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 21:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We all feel anxious from time to time. However, when anxiety starts to become a disruption to your life or the life of your loved one, you should learn more... <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all feel anxious from time to time. However, when anxiety starts to become a disruption to your life or the life of your loved one, you should learn more about anxiety disorders. If you cannot manage the care of your elderly loved one with anxiety,</p>
<div id="attachment_609" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/peppermint-palm-senior-care-senior-placement-miami-sacramento-anxiety-disorders-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-609" class="size-medium wp-image-609" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/peppermint-palm-senior-care-senior-placement-miami-sacramento-anxiety-disorders-1-300x199.jpg" alt="Peppermint Palm Senior Care, Senior Placement, Miami, Sacramento" width="300" height="199" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-609" class="wp-caption-text">Anxiety disorders in the elderly can cause paranoia</p></div>
<p>talk with a specialist at our agency to explore your options for outside care.</p>
<p>Anxiety disorders late in life can often be overlooked, since elders present anxiety disorders differently than younger people. In fact, anxiety disorders are twice as prevalent as dementia among older adults, and up to eight times more common than other major depressive disorders. Medications, Alzheimers, and Dementia may all exacerbate anxiety disorders.</p>
<p>The major types of anxiety disorders in older people are summarized here:</p>
<p>-Post-traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD): Acute stress disorder that lasts longer than a month</p>
<p>-Generalized Anxiety Disorder: Excessive worrying</p>
<p>-Panic Attacks: Sudden fear and dread</p>
<p>-Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder (OCD): Thoughts that produce intense anxiety that can only be calmed by an action</p>
<p>Talk therapy, medication, working with a therapist, social worker, or skilled counselor have all been shown as effective treatments. Consult a physician or gerontologist to get help or learn more.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>The post <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Guide for Single Seniors</title>
		<link>/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Most seniors or baby boomers have children or a large extended family to take care of them when they are eventually unable to. Statistics have shown that an increasing number... <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">A Guide for Single Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-512 alignright" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-200x300.jpg" alt="elderly-114328_1280" width="200" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-682x1024.jpg 682w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1.jpg 853w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a>Most seniors or baby boomers have children or a large extended family to take care of them when they are eventually unable to. Statistics have shown that an increasing number of baby boomers that are retiring never married or had children. If you fit into this category, you may be worried about who will take care of you when you no longer can. The care advisor experts here at Peppermint Palm Senior Care have put together a straightforward guide to help you with this matter and put your mind at ease.</p>
<p>You may think that you can rely on extended family, say a niece or nephew to take care of you and your well-being, but that may not always be the case. Many seniors are turning to a lawyer to protect them and act on their behalf which would include asset protection and care coordination. A lawyer can also help with keeping you financially sound and getting all of your assets in order. Loneliness can cause health problems in the long run for seniors as well, so being around as many people as possible will help. Form or join groups within the community and do activities that you love to keep your mind sharp and your “family” growing.</p>
<p>Single seniors deserve to get all the proper care they need just as much as seniors with children and extended families. If you have any questions about<a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/"> senior living in San Francisco</a>, or<a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/"> senior placement in Florida</a>, general senior care questions, feel free to contact us!</p>The post <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">A Guide for Single Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senior Placement Service in Florida</title>
		<link>/senior-placement-service-in-florida/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 20:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boomers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior assisted living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior placement services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Famous for its coastline, thousands flock to the wonderful state of Florida every year to visit its sand beaches. It is definitely the “Sunshine State”! Whether walking down the beach, practicing their... <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">Senior Placement Service in Florida</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_561" style="width: 222px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1.gif" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-561" class="size-medium wp-image-561" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-212x300.gif" alt="Senior assisted living florida senior placement services florida" width="212" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-212x300.gif 212w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-768x1087.gif 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-723x1024.gif 723w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-561" class="wp-caption-text">Senior assisted living florida senior placement services florida</p></div>
<p>Famous for its coastline, thousands flock to the wonderful state of Florida every year to visit its sand beaches. It is definitely the “Sunshine State”! Whether walking down the beach, practicing their backhand on the courts, or teeing up at a grassy gold course, seniors who chose assisted living in Florida with the help of Peppermit Palm will never miss an exciting day!</p>
<p>In Florida, assisted living facilities or ALFs serve loved ones who can no longer live at home, need more specific care, or who have Dementia or Alzheimers. There are over 1000 ALFs in Florida alone! It can be a lot to sift through without caring, experienced help.</p>
<p>Peppermint Palm Senior Care, Inc. is now offering <a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/">senior placement in Florida</a>. We are certified by the Florida Care Planning Council.</p>
<div id="attachment_529" style="width: 160px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/CPCStateLogosFL-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-529" class="size-full wp-image-529" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/CPCStateLogosFL-1.jpg" alt="Senior Assisted living senior placement services florida" width="150" height="149" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-529" class="wp-caption-text">Senior Assisted living senior placement services florida</p></div>
<p>We are a top agency for finding <a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/">assisted living in Florida</a> and now want to help your family in Florida! Use our years of experience and knowledge to find the right assisted living facility in Florida for your family today. Call us now, we&#8217;re here for you 24/7!</p>The post <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">Senior Placement Service in Florida</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
