<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>General | Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/general/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Placement Services</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 21:00:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.5</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</title>
		<link>/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 21:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>We all feel anxious from time to time. However, when anxiety starts to become a disruption to your life or the life of your loved one, you should learn more... <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We all feel anxious from time to time. However, when anxiety starts to become a disruption to your life or the life of your loved one, you should learn more about anxiety disorders. If you cannot manage the care of your elderly loved one with anxiety,</p>
<div id="attachment_609" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/peppermint-palm-senior-care-senior-placement-miami-sacramento-anxiety-disorders-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-609" class="size-medium wp-image-609" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/peppermint-palm-senior-care-senior-placement-miami-sacramento-anxiety-disorders-1-300x199.jpg" alt="Peppermint Palm Senior Care, Senior Placement, Miami, Sacramento" width="300" height="199" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-609" class="wp-caption-text">Anxiety disorders in the elderly can cause paranoia</p></div>
<p>talk with a specialist at our agency to explore your options for outside care.</p>
<p>Anxiety disorders late in life can often be overlooked, since elders present anxiety disorders differently than younger people. In fact, anxiety disorders are twice as prevalent as dementia among older adults, and up to eight times more common than other major depressive disorders. Medications, Alzheimers, and Dementia may all exacerbate anxiety disorders.</p>
<p>The major types of anxiety disorders in older people are summarized here:</p>
<p>-Post-traumatic Stress Disorder (PTSD): Acute stress disorder that lasts longer than a month</p>
<p>-Generalized Anxiety Disorder: Excessive worrying</p>
<p>-Panic Attacks: Sudden fear and dread</p>
<p>-Obsessive-Compulsive Disorder (OCD): Thoughts that produce intense anxiety that can only be calmed by an action</p>
<p>Talk therapy, medication, working with a therapist, social worker, or skilled counselor have all been shown as effective treatments. Consult a physician or gerontologist to get help or learn more.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>The post <a href="/anxiety-disorders-in-the-elderly/">Anxiety Disorders in the Elderly</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Guide for Single Seniors</title>
		<link>/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 13:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Most seniors or baby boomers have children or a large extended family to take care of them when they are eventually unable to. Statistics have shown that an increasing number... <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">A Guide for Single Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-512 alignright" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-200x300.jpg" alt="elderly-114328_1280" width="200" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-200x300.jpg 200w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1-682x1024.jpg 682w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/elderly-114328_1280-1.jpg 853w" sizes="(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px" /></a>Most seniors or baby boomers have children or a large extended family to take care of them when they are eventually unable to. Statistics have shown that an increasing number of baby boomers that are retiring never married or had children. If you fit into this category, you may be worried about who will take care of you when you no longer can. The care advisor experts here at Peppermint Palm Senior Care have put together a straightforward guide to help you with this matter and put your mind at ease.</p>
<p>You may think that you can rely on extended family, say a niece or nephew to take care of you and your well-being, but that may not always be the case. Many seniors are turning to a lawyer to protect them and act on their behalf which would include asset protection and care coordination. A lawyer can also help with keeping you financially sound and getting all of your assets in order. Loneliness can cause health problems in the long run for seniors as well, so being around as many people as possible will help. Form or join groups within the community and do activities that you love to keep your mind sharp and your “family” growing.</p>
<p>Single seniors deserve to get all the proper care they need just as much as seniors with children and extended families. If you have any questions about<a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/"> senior living in San Francisco</a>, or<a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/"> senior placement in Florida</a>, general senior care questions, feel free to contact us!</p>The post <a href="/a-guide-for-single-seniors-2/">A Guide for Single Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senior Placement Service in Florida</title>
		<link>/senior-placement-service-in-florida/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 20:20:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boomers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior assisted living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior placement services]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Famous for its coastline, thousands flock to the wonderful state of Florida every year to visit its sand beaches. It is definitely the “Sunshine State”! Whether walking down the beach, practicing their... <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">Senior Placement Service in Florida</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_561" style="width: 222px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1.gif" class="broken_link"><img decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-561" class="size-medium wp-image-561" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-212x300.gif" alt="Senior assisted living florida senior placement services florida" width="212" height="300" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-212x300.gif 212w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-768x1087.gif 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/10/senior-assisted-living-florida-placement-services-Peppermint-Palm-1-723x1024.gif 723w" sizes="(max-width: 212px) 100vw, 212px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-561" class="wp-caption-text">Senior assisted living florida senior placement services florida</p></div>
<p>Famous for its coastline, thousands flock to the wonderful state of Florida every year to visit its sand beaches. It is definitely the “Sunshine State”! Whether walking down the beach, practicing their backhand on the courts, or teeing up at a grassy gold course, seniors who chose assisted living in Florida with the help of Peppermit Palm will never miss an exciting day!</p>
<p>In Florida, assisted living facilities or ALFs serve loved ones who can no longer live at home, need more specific care, or who have Dementia or Alzheimers. There are over 1000 ALFs in Florida alone! It can be a lot to sift through without caring, experienced help.</p>
<p>Peppermint Palm Senior Care, Inc. is now offering <a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/">senior placement in Florida</a>. We are certified by the Florida Care Planning Council.</p>
<div id="attachment_529" style="width: 160px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/CPCStateLogosFL-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" aria-describedby="caption-attachment-529" class="size-full wp-image-529" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/CPCStateLogosFL-1.jpg" alt="Senior Assisted living senior placement services florida" width="150" height="149" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-529" class="wp-caption-text">Senior Assisted living senior placement services florida</p></div>
<p>We are a top agency for finding <a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/">assisted living in Florida</a> and now want to help your family in Florida! Use our years of experience and knowledge to find the right assisted living facility in Florida for your family today. Call us now, we&#8217;re here for you 24/7!</p>The post <a href="/senior-placement-service-in-florida/">Senior Placement Service in Florida</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Pet Therapy Can Benefit Assisted Living Seniors</title>
		<link>/how-pet-therapy-can-benefit-assisted-living-seniors-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 17:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/?p=517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pet therapy is a relatively new treatment for seniors in assisted living situations. Generally, pets offer comfort and companionship to their owners while being a part of the family. Owning... <a href="/how-pet-therapy-can-benefit-assisted-living-seniors-2/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/how-pet-therapy-can-benefit-assisted-living-seniors-2/">How Pet Therapy Can Benefit Assisted Living Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1.jpg" class="broken_link"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" class=" size-medium wp-image-505 alignright" src="http://03d48ba.netsolhost.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1-300x169.jpg" alt="dog-200942_1280" width="300" height="169" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2015/08/dog-200942_1280-1.jpg 1280w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></a>Pet therapy is a relatively new treatment for seniors in assisted living situations. Generally, pets offer comfort and companionship to their owners while being a part of the family. Owning a pet can add new life to a senior, giving them a reason to keep active all while reducing stress and improving their general health. There are some guidelines you should be aware of before getting a pet for a senior, or having a senior interact with an animal, and how they can add a natural sense of nurturing to the person.</p>
<p>Pet therapy isn’t approved at all assisted living communities, but seniors can always reap the benefits of having an animal around. Approved handlers will either bring dogs, cats, or more recently, bunnies! Pets add an emotional bond that can really bring out the joy of a senior, as well as keeping them in positive spirits. Some seniors may feel comfort interacting with the animal, maybe talking to the handler about the pets they’ve owned of current pets, or just like the comfort of having an animal around. Owning a pet can add another dimension as the person can ultimately bond with the animal and give them a resolve to care for the animal.</p>
<p>If a loved one is currently in <a href="http://peppermintpalmseniorcare.com/">assisted living in Sacramento</a> or if you are considering your options, pet therapy would be a great way to keep in a better mood and improve their overall health!</p>The post <a href="/how-pet-therapy-can-benefit-assisted-living-seniors-2/">How Pet Therapy Can Benefit Assisted Living Seniors</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When should one consider a nursing home or assisted living?</title>
		<link>/when-should-one-consider-a-nursing-home-or-assisted-living/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://00043ph.myregisteredwp.com/?p=92</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Nursing homes provide the highest levels of care, both medical and custodial. If you’re not sure that you or your loved one needs that level of care for the long-term,... <a href="/when-should-one-consider-a-nursing-home-or-assisted-living/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/when-should-one-consider-a-nursing-home-or-assisted-living/">When should one consider a nursing home or assisted living?</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nursing homes provide the highest levels of care, both medical and custodial. If you’re not sure that you or your loved one needs that level of care for the long-term, learn more about other types of senior housing, including In-Home care by contacting one of our highly trained Senior Advocates to see what will best fit your needs.</p>
<p>In one of the following circumstances, one should consider assisted living:</p>
<p><strong>Mental Health: Depression, anxiety, psychosis or dementia</strong></p>
<p><strong>Physical Health:</strong> The risk of falls may be too great, chronic diseases or physical disability that cause difficulty performing activities of daily living (ADL’s) walking, dressing, bathing, and preparing meals. Danger of wandering off or forgetting about the hot stove.</p>
<p><strong>Support systems:</strong> Caregivers are often juggling work, their own family responsibilities, and their own health. It is not possible for one person to be awake and responsible 24-hours a day. Lack of a support system, such as family and friends who can be called in an emergency and are able to assist in their needs. In-Home care services can also provide support a caregiver needs.</p>
<p><strong>Finances: Difficulty in managing financial obligations.</strong></p>The post <a href="/when-should-one-consider-a-nursing-home-or-assisted-living/">When should one consider a nursing home or assisted living?</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Survey Discusses Long-Term Elder Care Experiences</title>
		<link>/survey-discusses-long-term-elder-care-experiences/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://00043ph.myregisteredwp.com/?p=96</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The world of caregiving and elder care is always changing with each new generation. If you’re a caregiver yourself or have an aging loved one, you might be wondering how... <a href="/survey-discusses-long-term-elder-care-experiences/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/survey-discusses-long-term-elder-care-experiences/">Survey Discusses Long-Term Elder Care Experiences</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The world of caregiving and elder care is always changing with each new generation. If you’re a caregiver yourself or have an aging loved one, you might be wondering how other people like you are feeling about the current state of elder care in the U.S.</p>
<p>The Associated Press-NORC Center for Public Affairs Research recently released their research from a survey that sought to ask these very questions. Specifically, their study aimed to gauge Americans’ views on aging and caregiving, as well as provide suggestions for how to improve long-term elder care. The findings were quite interesting and dynamic.</p>
<p>To start, the study showed that the majority of subjects had experience with long-term care. A full 60 percent of Americans age 40 and over have experience receiving or providing long-term care. Furthermore, 90 percent of the people in this group have provided help to family members at some point, with 17 percent both receiving care and caring for others.</p>
<p>Often when people hear the term “caregiving”, they think of senior care. Interestingly enough, the most common form of elder care is family caregiving, as children frequently take care of aging parents. Family caregiving was utilized at some point by 83 percent of individuals who also have experience with assisted living.</p>
<p>On a related note, many respondents in the study didn’t realize the relative affordability of assisted living. Respondents in each group overestimated the price of assisted living facilities. In fact, 43 percent of individuals overestimated these costs by more than $500.</p>
<p>Considering that caregiving and/or elder care has affected a large portion of the U.S. population, how do these individuals regard their experiences?</p>
<p>Most survey respondents said that their experience with caregiving was favorable overall.</p>
<p>Over 70 percent of people stated that caring for a loved one was a positive, valuable life experience. Most respondents also said that the experience had strengthened their relationship with the person receiving care.</p>
<p>However, many caregivers know that although caring for a loved one can be incredibly rewarding, it can also take a toll on you. The AARP recommends preparing for the caregiving process before a loved one needs help. This will help save you some stress and create an environment that allows both you and your loved one to have a more positive experience. If you’re caring for a special person in your life, explore all your care options together and decide what the best course of action is for your family.</p>The post <a href="/survey-discusses-long-term-elder-care-experiences/">Survey Discusses Long-Term Elder Care Experiences</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Case Managers — What are they &#038; why are they important?</title>
		<link>/case-managers-what-are-they-why-are-they-important/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 12:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://00043ph.myregisteredwp.com/?p=99</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Case managers can be a valuable part of a senior’s healthcare. Most have a degree in social work or health counseling and their main job is to help coordinate a... <a href="/case-managers-what-are-they-why-are-they-important/">read more <i class="fa fa-chevron-circle-right"></i></a></p>
The post <a href="/case-managers-what-are-they-why-are-they-important/">Case Managers — What are they & why are they important?</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Case managers can be a valuable part of a senior’s healthcare. Most have a degree in social work or health counseling and their main job is to help coordinate a patient’s whole healthcare regimen. Case managers are jack-of-all-trades, using creativity and flexibility to help you and your senior in all sorts of ways. Navigating the medical world can be a stressful and confusing task. In some cases, it can be impossible for someone without the proper training.</p>
<p>A case manager often has a long list of contacts in the health care industry, helping patients pick the right provider for their needs. They can help you pick a doctor, a specialist, a hospital or nursing home. The manager will then coordinate with the provider to arrange appointment times, insurance information and other special needs. It can be hard for you to know for sure if your senior is getting the care they need. A case manager follows the treatments ensure that everything is in order. Think of a case manager as the spokesperson between your senior and the medical community. Their other tasks include day-to-day medical assistance for the patient, such as monitoring drug reactions and treatment progression.</p>
<p>Case managers are an important part of the medical community. Don’t over stress yourself by trying to take on the burden of coordinating your senior’s medical regimen. Case managers are trained to do just that.</p>The post <a href="/case-managers-what-are-they-why-are-they-important/">Case Managers — What are they & why are they important?</a> first appeared on <a href="/">Peppermint Palm Placement Services - Senior Care, Senior Care Advisor| Sacramento, CA</a>.]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
